Guide to the Charles Owen Rice Papers, 1894-2005 AIS.1976.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Subject Files, 1894-2005; I.
  - East Timor, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ebert, Joe, Correspondence, 1942-1946 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Eby, Kermit, Assistant Professor of Social Science, University of Chicago, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Economic Union Party, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Education Study Committee, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Egypt Trip, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Emerson Electric Company, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Engineers and Architects, AFL, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Eucharistic Rally, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Eye Opener, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fair Employment Practice, Committee on, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Fair Rent Committee, Radio Broadcasts, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Farm Equipment and Metal Workers Union, 1947-1950 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Farmers Union, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "Father K- a Living Newspaper of 1919 Strike", undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Fight for Freedom Committee, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Filitich, Michael, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Fireman's Protection Association, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - First Solemn High Masses, 1960-1966 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Fisher Scientific, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Flaccus Glass Company, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Forever Action Together, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Form Letters, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Forward, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - France and Ireland Trip, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Fraternal Order of Police, Riot Fact Finding Committee, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Freeman, Joshua B. "Catholics, Communists and Republicans", undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Frey, Reverend Donald R., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Fur and Leather Workers Union, 1937-1950 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Gaeth, Arthur, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Gagetta, "Pittsburgh Catholic History", c. 1995 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Gallagher, Meghan, "You Can Call Him Boss... David L. Lawrence", 2001 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Ghetto Parishes, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Gimbel's Strike, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Glass, Ceramic and Silica Sand Workers Union, Federation of, 1941-1949 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Governor's Commission on Capital Punishment, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Governor's Justice Commission, Allegheny Regional Council, 1976-1984 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Governor's Justice Commission, Allegheny Regional Council, 1976-1984 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Grubstake, Inc., 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Gustafson, Frederick E., "US Catholic Social Doctrine: John A. Ryan", 1990 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Halfway House, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Harper, Oliver J., Correspondence, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Hastings College, Nebraska, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Haden, William, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Hathaway Debate, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Headstart Program, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Health Care for Aged, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Heinz, H.J., Union, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Higgins, George G., 1988, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Holland, Hon. Elmer J., 1961 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Holland, Rosemary, "Catholic Radical Alliance", 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Holy Name Society, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Holy Rosary School, 1968, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Homestead Strike, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Homewood-Brushton Alliance, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Administration, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Announcements and Agendas, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Committee Minutes, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Committee Minutes, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Education, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Employment/Economic Opportunity, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Executive Committee Minutes, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Executive Committee Minutes, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Executive Committee Minutes, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Executive Committee Minutes, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Executive Committee Minutes, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Executive Committee Minutes, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Executive Committee Minutes, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Financial Statements, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Health, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Housing, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Homewood-Brushton Citizens Renewal Council, Inter-Agency Meeting Minutes, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Homewood-Brushton Community Convention, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Homewood-Brushton Community Health Clinic, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Homewood Chamber of Commerce, 1966, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Homewood Post Office Dedication, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Hormel Lockout, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Hormel Lockout, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Hospital Strikes, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Hospital Unions, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Hospital Unions, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Hospital Workers, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Hotel and Restaurant Workers Union, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Houde Case, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Hour of Faith Broadcasts, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Housing, 1939-1940, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Housing Authority, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Housing Conference, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Housing, Fair Rent Committee, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Housing, Soho Renewal, Terrace Village, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Howell, Reverend Clifford SJ, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Hubbard and Co., Work Stoppage, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Immaculate Conception Church, Washington, PA, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Immigration and Naturalization Committee, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Independent Unions, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Industrial Relations Center, University of Chicago, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Information Requests, General, 1947-1949 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Institute of Adult Education, Catholic Diocese of Pittsburgh, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Interfaith Housing, Agendas, 1967-1974 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Interfaith Housing, Bethel Park Housing, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Interfaith Housing, By-Laws, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Interfaith Housing, Citizens-Clergy Coordinating Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Interfaith Housing, Contracts, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Interfaith Housing, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Interfaith Housing, Correspondence, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Interfaith Housing, Correspondence, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Interfaith Housing, Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Interfaith Housing, Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Interfaith Housing, Description and Goals, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Interfaith Housing, Financial Records, 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Interfaith Housing, HUD News, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Interfaith Housing, Income Guidelines for Public Housing, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Interfaith Housing, Journal of Home Ownership, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Interfaith Housing, Lists of Board of Directors, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Interfaith Housing, Mini Corporate Association Newsletter, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Interfaith Housing, Minutes, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Interfaith Housing, Minutes, 1970-1974 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Interfaith Housing, More Than Bricks and Mortar, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Interfaith Housing, News, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Interfaith Housing, News Clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Interfaith Housing, Operation Breakthrough, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Interfaith Housing, Pamphlets on Housing, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Interfaith Housing, Pamphlets on Pittsburgh Housing, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Interfaith Housing, Proposals, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Interfaith Housing, Reports, 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Interfaith Housing, Resumes, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Interfaith Housing, St. Eudes Property, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Interfaith Housing, United Movement for Progress, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Interfaith Housing, United States Steel Prefabricated Houses, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Interfaith Housing, Urban Action and Experimentation Program, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Interfaith Housing, Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh Hill Renewal, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers, 1937-1950 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - International Electrical Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers, 1962-1973 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - International Hotel and Restaurant Workers Alliance, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - International Human Rights Day, "Continuing the Legacy of Charles Owen Rice", 2005 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - International Jewelry Workers Union, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - International Ladies Garment Workers Union, 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - International Longshoremen and Warehousemen, 1948-1950 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    Bridges, Harry
  - International Moulders and Foundry Union, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - International Photo Engravers Union, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - International Typographical Union, 1947-1949 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - International Union of Electrical Workers, 1950-1957 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - International Union of Elevator Constructors, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - International Union of United Auto Workers, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - International Union of the United Brewery Workers Union, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Interview, "My Anti-Communism", 1982 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Ireland, 1970-1979 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Ireland, Economic and Political Conditions, 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Ireland, Labor Relations, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Ireland, Radharc Films, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Ireland Trip, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Ireland Trip, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Ireland Trips, 1962-1982 [1890, 1910] (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Ireland Trip, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ireland Trip, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Ireland Trip, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Irish-American Unity Conference, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Irish Relief Charity, c. 1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Irish Republican Army, 1977-1991 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Irish Republican Socialist Party, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Israel Bonds, 1962-1966 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Israel Trip, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Italian Communists, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Jefferson Memorial Cemetery Strike, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Jehovah's Witnesses, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Jitneys, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Johnson, Dr. Dennis C., 1973 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Jones and Laughlin, Local 1211, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Jubilee, 25th, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Jubilee, 40th, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Jubilee, 45th, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Jubilee, 50th, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Juvenile Court, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Kane, John, J., 1940-1946 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Keener, Reverend Joseph, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Kohler Strike, 1960, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Kulpmont, PA., 1949 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Labor, 1970-1990 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Labor, 1984-1992 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Labor Award, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Labor and Communism, 1977-1997 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Labor Day, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Labor Day, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Labor Day, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Labor Day, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Labor Day, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Labor Day, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Labor Day, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Labor Day, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Labor Day, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Labor Day, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Labor Day, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Labor Day, 1979-1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Labor Day Award, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Labor, General Clippings, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Labor Holiday Luncheons, 1961-1967 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Labor Honors, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Labor, general clippings
  - Labor, Interview with Msgr Rice by Ronald L Filippelli, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Labor Issues, 1953-1958 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Labor, Miscellaneous, 1950, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Labor, Miscellaneous, 1950, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Labor, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1947-1951 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Labor Peace, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - LaRoche College Strike, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Laundry Workers International Union, 1938-1947 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Lawrence, David L., 1945-1946, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Lawrence, David L., 1945-1946, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Lewis, John L., 1959-1961 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Liberty Bakery Strike, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Liberty Bakery Strike, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Liquor Control, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Local Developers, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Loyola University of Los Angeles, Correspondence, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Lynd, Alice and Staughton, "Liberation Theology for Quakers", c. 1992 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - MacBride Principles, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - MacBride, Sean, 1977-1982 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Machinists Union, 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Man of the Year, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - March 11, 1966 - Msgr. Rice Day in Pittsburgh (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - March for Peace in Central America, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Marine and Shipbuilders Union, 1947-1949 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Marriage Conferences, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Matthew, Brother, Correspondence, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - McCabe, W.F., Communism, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - McCarthy, Senator Joseph, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - McCollester, Charles J., "Irish in the Steel Industry", 1999 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - McDonald, David J., 1965 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - McDonough, Jack, 1981-1983 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - McIntyre, Reverend Carl, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Meat Cutters Union, 1947-1950 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Mechanics Educational Society of America, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Meetings, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Mellon, Richard King, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Mental Health, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Merovich, Peter, "Castle Shannon, The Patch- Mine #2", undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Merrill Lynch & Company (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Metropolitan Citizens Organization, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Midland Borough Council, Tri-State Conference on the Impact of Steel, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Milk and Ice Cream Salesmen Drivers, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Mine and Mill Workers Union, 1947-1950 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - The Miner's Voice, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Miscellaneous, 1951-1952 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Molony, Joseph P., 1955 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Monaghan, John P., "Above All Things the Truth", 1992 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Monsignorship Elevation, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Includes congratulatory letters and other related materials re: Rice's elevation to Domestic Prelate
  - Moorhead, Hon. William S., 1967 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Moral Rearmament, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Morgan, Congressman Thomas E., 1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Morocco, Ireland and Mexico Trips, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Murray, Mrs., Television Broadcast of Philip Murray, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Murray Motion Picture, Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Murray Motion Picture, Transcript, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Murray, Philip, book written by Charles Owen Rice, 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Murray, Philip, proposed book by Charles Owen Rice, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Murray, Philip, Life Magazine, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Murray, Philip, President, CIO, 1941-1946 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Nation, 1966-1969 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Washington, PA, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Health Committee, 1966-1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Washington, PA, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - National Association of Intergroup Relations Officials, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - National Broadcasting Corporation, "Marvelous Machines, Expendable People", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - National Catholic Conference for Interracial Justice, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - National Catholic Conference for Interracial Justice, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - National Catholic Education Association, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - National Catholic Reporter, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - National Catholic Social Action Conference, 1938-1939 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - National Catholic Social Action Conference, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - National Catholic Social Action Conference, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - National Catholic Social Action Conference, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - National Catholic Welfare Conference, 1939-1940 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - National Citizens Political Action Committee, 1939-1945 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - National Congress of Industrial Organization, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - National Council of Catholic Men, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Negro Education Emergency Drive, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Nelson, Steve, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - New City, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Newmeyer, George, Horoscope of Charles Owen Rice, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1976 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1977-1997 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Northern Ireland, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Northern Ireland Fundraising, 1971-1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Northern Ireland, Irish Catholic Reporter, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Northern Ireland, New York and Other Addresses, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Northern Ireland, Pittsburgh, 1971-1977 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Nursing Home Workers, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - O'Connor, Reverend Bill, 1982-1985 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Offender Aid and Restoration of Pennsylvania, Inc., 1975 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Office Employees Union, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Office Workers, 1947-1969 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Oil Workers, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Oomirigar, Jimmy, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Operation Progress, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Orders, Books, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Our Sunday Visitor, Articles and Correspondence, 1947-1950 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Our Sunday Visitor, Newspaper, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Our Sunday Visitor, Newspaper, 1990-1994 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Overseas Travel Company, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Packinghouse Workers, CIO, 1947-1952 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Panama, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Papal Encyclical Anniversary, Reconstructing, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Paret, Rufus S., 1945 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Paszkowski, Zygmont, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Pennsylvania Catholic Welfare Conference, 1964-1966 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Pennsylvania Labor History Society, 1973, 1995-1999 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Pennsylvania Prison Society, 1987-1991 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Pennsylvania State Human Relations Commission Publications, 1961-1964 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Permits, Postal, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Personal Official Documents, 1952-1976 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Peruvian Mission Collection, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Picketing, Article on, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Pittsburgh Area Religion and Race Council, 1966-1973 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Pittsburgh AIDS Task Force, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Pittsburgh Catholic, Clippings, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Pittsburgh Catholic Conference, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Pittsburgh Catholic History, [1850], 1994 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Pittsburgh City Council, Campaign for 1971, Campaign Issues (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Pittsburgh City Council, Campaign for 1971, Campaign Literature (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Pittsburgh City Council, Campaign for 1971, Contributions (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Pittsburgh City Council, Campaign for 1971, Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Pittsburgh City Council, Campaign for 1971, Crank Mail (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Pittsburgh City Council, Campaign for 1971, Finances (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Pittsburgh City Council, Campaign for 1971, Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Pittsburgh Community Study, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Pittsburgh Conference on Public Education, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Pittsburgh Courier, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Pittsburgh Hospital, 1966-1973 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh Hospital, Proposals and Policies, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Pittsburgh Irish, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Pittsburgh Press, Analysis of Article on Retail Store Employees Local 1407, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Pittsburgh Press Club, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Pittsburgh Press Strike, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1966-1969 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Pittsburgh Second Jubilee, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Pittsburgh Symphony Society, 1966-1970 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Pittsburgh Union Label Council, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Planned Parenthood, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Poems, 1941-1947, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Police Pension Fund, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Political Causes, 1968-1977 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Politics, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Politics, National, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Pornography, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Poverty Funding Cut Protest, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Press Releases, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Priests of the Catholic Diocese of Pittsburgh, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Priests' School for Social Action, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Prison Society of Southwestern Pennsylvania, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Prisoner Correspondence [RESTRICTED]
    Access Restrictions
    Individual Prisoners' Case Files, Correspondence, and other prisoner information from the Prison Society of Southwest Pennsylvania (Boxes 14-16) are closed until the prisoner's death, unless written permission is provided by the prisoner.
    - 1976, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1977, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1977, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1978, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 1978, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 1979, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 1979, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 1980, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - 1980, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - 1981, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - 1982, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - 1983, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - 1983, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - 1984, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - 1984, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - 1988, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - 1989, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - 1990, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - 1991, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - 1992, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - 1993, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - 1994, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - 1995, [RESTRICTED] (Box 14, Folder 23)